SURYAKIRAN AKKINAPELLI

2521 PIEDMONT RD NE 2309, ATLANTA, GA- 30324

www.linkedin.com/in/surya-kiran-akkinapelli Mobile: +1 404-932-8278 sakkinapelli1@student.gsu.edu

Data Engineer with 2+ years of experience in developing migration tools and scripts to handle huge datasets involving data preprocessing, analysis and API development. Dedicated professional with good problem-solving skills and capable of developing, integrating highly adaptive features to translate business requirements to deliverables. Looking for Summer 2022 internship roles in the field of Data Science and Analytics.

EXPERIENCE

STARR INSURANCE COMPANY

United States

Sprint project team member

August 2021 - December 2021

Responsible as a team member on a marketing-focused project involving machine learning, text analytics and dashboard presentation of results

• Created a dataset based on problem statements and analysed, extracted and added new features to generate an analytics framework.

ZENOTI India

<u>Data Engineer</u> April 2019 - July 2021

Responsible as a team member to build python scripts and tools to perform data migration activities for new and existing clients into the Zenoti domain

- Developed Python scripts, SQL scripts, API's and database table designs for data migration and web scrapping tasks.
- Enhanced performance of existing features by 20% and are in frequent use for migrating new clients.
- Achieved 'Rising Star' award for developing an automation tool to migrate data between stage and live domain sites for Zenoti clients used during the GoLive phase.
- Migrated code base from python2 to python3, added around 400 unit test cases for the data migration project to maintain and improve code completeness.
- Handled and resolved customer issues and escalations to ensure 100% smooth workflow in the client's business operations during the data migration phase.
- Enhanced and fixed issues in the test automation framework to execute test cases for the application for each release cycle to ensure 0 regression issues.
- Onboarded new employees into data migration team and monitored with tasks on a daily and weekly basis

ZENOTISoftware Engineer Intern

Hyderabad, India
January 2019 - March 2019

Responsible as a team member to fix customer escalations and improve performance of existing features

- Improved quality of features by 20% and fixed customer issues to improve usability of product with ease
- Developed API's to create and update a particular entity in Zenoti involved basic database table design, API, front end design and integrating these components.

PATH CREATORS
Hyderabad, India
Machine Learning Intern
May 2018 - June 2018

Responsible as a team member to solve a given problem using different Machine Learning algorithms

• Applied supervised machine learning algorithms: Logistic Regression, Random Forest, KNN and Decision Tree for dataset based on a business problem with an accuracy of 83%

EDUCATION

Georgia State University

Atlanta, GA

Masters in Data Science and Analytics, J.Mack Robinson College of Business

December 2022

- GPA: 4.07/4.0
- Relevant course work: Statistical foundations, Data Programming for Analytics, Data Management for Analytics, Data Visualization

India

SreeNidhi Institute of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology

May 2019

Hyderabad, India

- GPA: 4.0/4.0
- Relevant course work: Big Data Analysis, Data Warehouse and Data Mining, Cloud Computing, Python Programming, Data Science, Database Management Systems

SKILLS

- Languages and Technologies Python, SQL, R, JavaScript, Java, C#, C, API development, Web Scraping, MATLAB, pyspark
- Frameworks and Tools Informatica, Clementine, Arduino, Raspberry pi, Excel, Jupyter
- Database Microsoft SQL server, Oracle MYSQL
- Modules and Libraries Pandas, Numpy, Seaborn, Plotly, Selenium, BeautifulSoup

PROJECTS

Credit Card Lead Prediction

October 2021 - December 2021

• Implemented Supervised Machine Learning Algorithms to predict if a potential customer is interested in taking a new credit card or not from the bank, and got an accuracy of 83% for the Random Forest algorithm.

Estimize Insights Extraction

November 2021 - December 2021

- Extracted data from the Estimize site and stored it in the MySql database to get insights into financial data for various companies.
- Performed web scraping on the Estimize site with Selenium and BeautifulSoup in Python by handling all user interactions.

Visualizing Global COVID-19 Trends

November 2021 - November 2021

• Extracted insights of Covid-19 impact in the world and in the US by creating interactive plots using Plotly library in python by performing data pre-processing and analysis tasks.

Association Rule Mining using Eclat Algorithm

July 2018 - September 2018

• Obtained tweets for a given set of keywords from Twitter and implemented the Eclat algorithm to generate association rules.

Bit Coin Price Prediction

March 2018 - March 2018

• Performed time series analysis on bitcoin dataset using ARIMA model to predict the price of BitCoin for a given future date with an RSquared value of 0.757.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Qualified for ACM-ICPC (Global programming competition) regionals in 2018.
- Secured 4th place in the Data Science Hackathon conducted by JNTU-H(Jawaharlal Technological University in Hyderabad) in collaboration with Infogrex and Colaberry.

PUBLICATIONS AND PRESENTATIONS

- Hold a Patent with the name 'A SYSTEM AND A METHOD FOR SPEECH DETECTION AND HANDWRITING REPLICATION AND WRITING THEREOF' with application number: 202041009647.
- Presented a paper on "Stock market Prediction using neural networks and ARIMA" at the Rayat Bahra Group of Institutions, Punjab in the ICAST 2018 conference.

COURSES

- Data structures and Algorithms course at Smart Interviews.
- Machine Learning A-Z: Hands-On Python and R in Data Science from Udemy.